

ABDULHAKEEM ABIOYE

Oxford, Oxfordshire OX3 9NQ

+447895680135

wisdomabioye@gmail.com • https://abkabioye.me

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a seasoned software developer with more than five years of experience. I am committed to providing high-level solutions that drive business and deliver outstanding cost efficiency. I seek an interesting position to offer top-notch solutions as part of a progressive team.

EDUCATION

Master of Science - MS:

Environmental Impact Assessment and Management, May 2023 Oxford Brookes University - Oxford, **OXF**

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structure: Programming, 2016 FreeCodeCamp

Bachelor's degree: Geology/Earth

Science, 2015

Federal University of Technology -Minna

Diploma: Frontend and Backend Programming Basics, 2010 Lovelamp Systems - Ibadan

EXPERIENCE

Lead Developer [Remote Contract], 06/2022 to 06/2023

Ador - San Francisco, California

- Produce detailed feature designs based on specifications.
- Develop and implement features into the codebase.
- Integrate blockchain solutions to meet company demands.

Web Developer, 04/2018 to 06/2022 Simulate Link Nigeria Enterprises - Minna, Nigeria

- Implement website and integrate solutions into business operations.
- Ensures smooth running of a web application for daily workflow.

Instructor in Web Development, 01/2015 to 03/2018 Lovelamp Systems and Consulting Firm - Ibadan, Nigeria

- Educate students on HTML, CSS and JavaScript programming language, utilizing instructional techniques, including a hands-on curriculum.
- Design and update all instructional materials for IT programs regularly.
- Create guides and course materials to reiterate lecture information and help students.

Freelancer, 01/2011 to 03/2014 Rockstar Softlogic - Minna, Nigeria

- Propose, design and develop a website or an application for corporate organization/enterprise.
- Repairs laptops for lecturers and students.
- Fixes mobile phone (Blackberry and Android OS) software problems.
- Prepares presentations and Word documents using Microsoft Office.

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- JavaScript & Libraries
- HTML & CSS
- Node.js, Express & Modules
- MongoDB & Mongoose
- React
- Web3 & Blockchain Integration
- Solidity
- Typescript
- Next.is

- Vercel
- AWS
- · Digital Ocean
- Gcloud
- OS Installation
- · Linux & Windows
- MS Office (Excel, Powerpoint, Word)
- Computer Maintenance
- · Communication skills
- Problem-solving
- Fast Learner + Time Management